1800contacts.com 2004-06-04

# Privacy Policy | 1-800 CONTACTS

Privacy Policy -- Effective 10/11/2000 - Update 9/6/2002 

1-800 CONTACTS, INC. values its customers and respects their privacy. We don't disclose, sell, rent, or loan any information about you to any third party. We collect customer information to be able to process your order as well as improve your shopping experience and to communicate with you about our products, services, contests, surveys, and promotions. 1-800 CONTACTS, INC. recognizes that it must maintain and use customer information responsibly.

This policy describes the personal information we collect about you, why we collect it, and how we use it. Our policy also describes the choices you can make about how we collect and use your information. If you have any questions about our privacy policy, please contact one of our Customer Service Representatives by calling us at 1-800-CONTACTS (1-800-266-8228) or writing us at 51 West Center Street, Orem, UT 84020.

If our information practices change in the future, we will notify you by posting the policy changes directly to this Web page. We will post any such change before we use any of your information in any way other than as explicitly stated above.

Frequently Asked Questions:

What kind of information does 1-800 CONTACTS, INC. collect?   
How does 1-800 CONTACTS, INC. use my information?   
Does 1-800 CONTACTS, INC. share my information with third parties?   
How do I access my information? How do I update my information?   
How do I remove my information from e-mail or postal mailings?   
How does 1-800 CONTACTS, INC. protect children's privacy?   
What about links to other Internet sites and services?   
What are cookies? How does 1-800 CONTACTS, INC. use cookies on its Web site?   
How does 1-800 CONTACTS, INC. make sure my order information is secure?   

What kind of information does 1-800 CONTACTS, INC. collect?  
We collect information (such as your name, e-mail address, mailing address, contact lens prescription, phone number, credit card numbers, and the name and phone number of your eye care provider) that you provide when you place an order, register with us or participate in a contest, survey, or promotion. We also maintain a record of your historical purchases that are placed through the phone, mail, fax, e-mail, and over the Internet. Because all of our information systems are fully integrated, when you place an order with 1-800 CONTACTS, INC. your customer information is available to you through any channel through which you may choose to contact us (phone, postal mail, fax, Internet, or e-mail.)

1-800 CONTACTS is currently using and has contracted with Omniture, a third party, to track and analyze non-personally identifiable usage and volume statistical information from our visitors and customers to administer our web site in order to constantly improve the web site quality. All data collected by Omniture on behalf of 1-800 CONTACTS is owned and used by   
1-800 CONTACTS. 1-800 CONTACTS reserves the right to publish non-personally identifiable summary information regarding its web site visitors for promotional purposes and as a representative audience for advertisers. Please note that this is not personal information, only general summaries of the activities of our visitors and customers.

Omniture uses cookies to help track visitor behavior and sets cookies in behalf of 1-800 CONTACTS which will be listed under the domain 207.net. For more information about Omniture's privacy policy go to www.omniture.com.  

How does 1-800 CONTACTS, INC. use my information?  
When you make a purchase from 1-800 CONTACTS, INC., we use your information to process your order. We will also send you an e-mail to confirm your order, and we may need to contact you via phone, mail, or e-mail if we have any questions regarding your order. From time to time, we may send you e-mails to help us learn more about your shopping preferences so that we may better serve you in the future. In addition we may use that information to help us better improve our site design and your shopping experience. If you make a purchase from 1-800 CONTACTS, INC. we may also send you notices about our products, services, contests, surveys, and promotions or news about contact lenses through postal mail.

To better serve you, we combine information that you give us over the phone, mail, fax, e-mail, surveys, and over the Internet. This information is combined so that we may enhance and personalize your shopping experience, and to communicate with you by phone, e-mail, or postal mail about our products, services, contests, surveys, and promotions that may be of interest to you.

Does 1-800 CONTACTS, INC. share my information with third parties?  
Unlike some of our competitors, we do not share your personal information with any third or outside party. We do not disclose, sell, rent, or loan any information about you to any third parties.

Please note: On all orders placed, 1-800 CONTACTS, INC. does attempt to verify or obtain a contact lens prescription from an eye care provider that you designate. This information is held under the same strict confidentially standards as described above. 

How do I access my information? How do I update my information?  
To access your information, simply click "Existing Customer" on the home page (www.contacts.com) and enter in your home phone, and your e-mail address or the last four digits of your credit card number. This will bring up your customer account and from this point you can make changes to your personal information. If at any time you would like us to update your customer information or remove you from our e-mail or postal mail lists, feel free to contact one of our Customer Service Representatives by calling 1-800-CONTACTS (1-800-266-8228).

How do I remove my information from e-mail or postal mailing lists?  
If you prefer not to receive information from us, either through e-mail or postal mail, please let us know by sending us an e-mail or calling one of our Customer Service Representatives at 1-800-CONTACTS (1-800-266-8228).

Please note: Such requests may take up to 6-8 weeks to become effective. In addition, if you ask to remove your name and address from our e-mail or postal mailing lists, we will maintain your name in a "do not mail" file to ensure that we can honor your request. Also, when you make a purchase, we will send you e-mails to confirm your order and may also need to contact you via phone, postal mail, or e-mail if we have other questions regarding your order. 

How does 1-800 CONTACTS, INC. protect children's privacy?  
Like you, we at 1-800 CONTACTS, INC. are concerned about the safety of children when they use the Internet. Consistent with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998, we will never request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13.

If we become aware that a subscriber is under the age of 13 and has registered without prior verifiable parental consent, we will remove his or her personally identifiable registration information from our files.

What about links to other Internet sites and services?  
1-800 CONTACTS, INC. may maintain links to other sites that are not under our control. These Web sites have their own policies regarding privacy, which you should review before visiting them. We have no responsibility for linked Web sites and provide these links solely for the convenience and information of our customers. 

Internet Security:  
How does 1-800 CONTACTS, INC. make sure my order information is secure?

Protecting your order information is a priority for us. We use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology to protect the security of your online order information.

More than 90% of Fortune 500 companies use SSL security to protect their sensitive information. SSL security makes eavesdropping on the Internet nearly impossible. When you use our secure ordering page you can be assured that your sensitive information and monetary transactions with  
1-800 CONTACTS, INC. are encrypted, safe, and secure.

To check the security of your connection, look at the lower left-hand corner of your browser window after accessing the server. If you see an unbroken key or a closed lock (depending on your browser), the SSL is active and the server is secure. You can also double-check by looking at the URL line of your browser. When assessing a secure server, the first characters of the site address will change from "http://" to "https://."

Some versions of browsers and some firewalls don't allow or permit communication through secure servers. In that case, we have established a "Standard Server" option that you may select. This option is available on the Home page and is located just below the "Existing Customer" button. This connection does not use SSL technology and is not secure. If you can't access either of these servers or for any reason and would like to place your order by calling one of our Customer Service Representatives please dial 1-800-CONTACTS (1-800-266-8228).

Adware:

1-800 CONTACTS, INC. does not participate with or use third party services such as Gator.com, whenu.com or ezula.com. 1-800 CONTACTS, INC. has determined that there are instances where this type of advertising could be construed as confusing for customers. Therefore, 1-800 CONTACTS, INC. is in the process of taking steps to ensure that these third party adware services do not function on the 1-800 CONTACTS, INC. website. www.1800contacts.com

Cookies:  
What are cookies? How does 1-800 CONTACTS, INC. use cookies on its site?

A cookie is a small file that Web sites often store on your computer's hard drive when you visit their sites. A cookie may contain information that is used to track the pages of the sites you've visited.

We use cookies in order to improve your shopping experience. When you visit the 1-800 CONTACTS, INC. Web site, your cookie helps us keep track of your order as you shop at our site. If you are a registered customer, your cookie allows us to recognize you when you return to our site and provides you with access to your account information. If you register with or order from us, we also use cookies to monitor and maintain information about your use of our Web site in a manner that identifies you as a customer. This information helps us serve you better by improving our site design, as well as our products, services, contests, surveys, and promotions.

You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser. If you turn off cookies, though, we will not be able to track your order or enable you to make a purchase from our site. Nor will we be able to recognize you as a registered user to allow you access to your account information.

To enable cookies on your browser:

AOL 5.0:  
Select "Preferences"  
Click on "WWW"  
Select the "Security" tab  
Click on "Custom Level"  
Scroll down to "Cookies"  
Select "Enable" 

Netscape Navigator/Communicator:  
Select "Preferences"from the "Edit" menu  
Select "Advanced" from the left hand menu  
Select "Accept All Cookies"  
Click "OK" 

Internet Explorer 5.0 for PC:  
Select "Internet Options" from the "Tools" menu  
Click the "Security" tab  
Click "Custom Level" at the bottom of the window  
Scroll down to "Cookies"  
Select "Always accept cookies"  
Click "OK" 

Internet Explorer 5.0 for Mac:  
Select "Preferences" from the "Edit" menu  
Select "Receiving Files"  
Select the option "Never ask" under "When receiving cookies"  
Click "OK"
